わあっ　はあ いっ… ディー はあ はあ…
Dii! You've come for me!
来てくれたんだね
So he awoke of his own will...
自らの意志で覚醒したか
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
They were defeated by some sort of immense power?
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね) を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
何か 強大な力に阻まれただと？
Where the Heart Lies
Yes.
はい
某が駆けつけた時には ハウエンクアたちの
アブ・カムゥは 既に破壊されており
When I had come to their aid
the Avu Kamu belonging to Hauenkua's
troops were already destroyed.
You're telling me there's a force that
can go against the Avu Kamu?
アブ・カムゥに対する
力があるというのか
Hakuoro...
ハクオロ
What have you done?
一体何をした？
I beg your pardon, Your Highness.
恐れながら 聖上
If we continue like this, only the
path of destruction awaits us.
このまま進めば
我らには滅びの道しか待っておりませぬ
Your Highness, unification of
the lands is almost at hand.
聖上 全土統一は目前なのです
We cannot consider retreat.
撤退は考えられません
Your Highness, is this the
extent of your resolve!?
聖上の覚悟とは
その程度のものだったのですか
Hien, mind your words.
ヒエン 言葉が過ぎるぞ
It's all right, Genjimaru.
よい ゲンジマル
I made a vow
余は誓ったのだ
クンネカムンの民に 安住をと
to provide a safe existence for the
citizens of Kunekamun.
So you will turn all the nations
against us for that!?
ために 全てを敵に回すおつもりか！
It is too late for us to withdraw from this war!
この戦 もう引くわけには行かぬのだ
むう
What do you want of me?
私に 何か用か？
You can sense my presence.
某の気配に気付くか
Exactly. Who are you?
その方 何者だ
What are you up to by taking in Hauenkua?
ハウエンクアに取り入り 何をたくらむ
I am myself. No more than that.
私は私だ　それ以上のものではない
I have no interest in riddles.
謎掛けをするつもりは無い
If you will not answer me...
答えねば… うん？
You've grown old, Genjimaru.
老いたな ゲンジマル
The younger you wouldn't have
given an opponent any time.
以前のお前なら
相手に時間等など与えなかったものを
It couldn't be...
まさか
Could it be you?
あなた様は…
The time has come.
時は動き始めた
I'll need your help once again.
再び 汝の力を借りるぞ
It's too soon. Why?
早過ぎる
なぜ こんなにも早く 目覚められた
Why did he awaken so soon?
きゃっ　ふーふ
ヘっ ひいっ
Oh, you shouldn't do that, Aruruu!
もう　駄目でしょ アルルゥ
ふーん… ふかふか
So fluffy!
ふふ　ふっ ふっ ふっ ふーん
You shall offer me your very being.
我に 汝が全てを捧げよ
I... I...
私は… 私は
Does your stomach hurt?
お腹痛いの？
I will give you myself...
捧げます　身も心も 全てあなたに
Body and soul, I will give you everything!
捧げます
Now then, as for our plans from here...
さて 今後についてですが
Half our troops are gone, and of what's left,
only half can still function.
兵の数は半減　動ける者はさらに半数
Even if it's only half, we still have to fight!
半数だろうと 戦うまでだ
If we just fight...
ただ やみくもに戦えば…
Brother...
兄者 兄者！
Brother!
はっ…　すまない
I am sorry, carry on.
続けてくれ
What did you see that time?
君はあの時 何を見た
Do you know what happened to me?
私がどうなったのかを
君は知っているのか
This should ease your nerves
and calm you down.
これで動悸が治まって 落ち着くはずです
Eruruu, did you...
エルルゥ 君は… あっ
I'll bring you a change of clothing.
着替えを持ってきますね
Eruruu, wait...
エルルゥ ちょっ…
ううっ… 何だ
What is this?
This is...
これは…
Eruruu?
エルルゥ？
Are you feeling ill?
具合 悪いですか？
No, I am all...
いや 大丈… あっ
Oh, I'm sorry, but could you
get me a glass of water?
ああ すまないけど 水を１杯 くれないか
Yes.
はい
The mask...
仮面
What's going on?
一体 これは…
Are you awake, Iceman?
お目覚めかね アイスマン
Mr. Mizushima...
ミズシマさん
How are you feeling?
Have you remembered anything?
気分はどうだね
何か思い出したかね
No, I am sorry.
いえ　すみません
I see.
そうか　その仮面のことだけでも
思い出してくれれば 助かるのだが
If you could at least remember something
about that mask, it would be helpful.
Yes, sir.
はい
By the way, has Number 3510
been a bother to you?
ところで 3510号は
君に迷惑を掛けてないかね？
She is no bother at all!
She has been very good to me.
迷惑なんてとんでもない
彼女は良くしてくれています
However, why do you call her by a number?
しかし なぜ番号で呼んでいるのですか？
An experimental subject cannot be given a name.
実験体には人の名前は付けられない
Those are the rules.
そういう決まりなのだから
Experimental subject?
実験体…
That is an unpleasant rule.
嫌な決まりですね
If you don't mind, can you give her a name?
良かったら その子に
名前を付けてやってくれないか
While I can't call her by a name,
I'm sure they won't mind it if you do.
私が名を呼ぶことはできないが
君が呼ぶのなら構わないだろう
Well then, I'll be going.
では 私はこれで
Give her a lovely name.
素敵な名前を付けてやってくれ
A name, huh?
名前か
What kind of name would you like?
どんな名前がいい？
Or do you not need a name?
それとも 名前なんかいらないか
The professor refers to me as Number 3510.
3510号って 博士が付けてくれたから
I know... 3, 5, 1, 0...
そうだな　３ ５ １ ０
San... Go... Mi... Mi...
３ ５　ミ ミ ミコ…
Mi... Ko...
Mi... Ko... To...
ミコト
Mikoto!
Mikoto?
あっ 駄目か
No good?
Mikoto... Mikoto...
ミコト
I'm very, very happy, Hakuoro-san.
とっても とっても うれしいです
ハクオロさん
Hakuoro-san...
Please snap out of it, Hakuoro-san!
しっかりしてください ハクオロさん
ううはっ
Hakuoro-san?
ハクオロさん？
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
This place...
ここは？
What just happened?
今のは 一体…
はあ おじいちゃん
Grandpa!
あと少しだというのに
Just a little bit farther...
Sakuya, you hide here.
サクヤは ここで隠れておるのだ
Grandpa...
おじいちゃん
Have at you!
参る！
That's...
ありゃあ…
The Avu Kamu!
アブ・カムゥ
He stopped that blow!
受け止めやがった
うむっ
That guy... Who the heck is he?
あいつ 何者だ
It's been a while, Genjimaru, Sakuya.
久しいな　ゲンジマル　サクヤ
It has been a while, King Hakuoro.
お久しゅうございまする　ハクオロ皇
Let us hear your story.
話を聞こう
Kunekamun is going down
the path of destruction.
クンネカムンは
破滅の道を歩みつつあります
Instead of coexistence, they seek
to control the other people.
他族との共存を拒み 全てを支配し
Even if they do unite all the land,
eventually resentment will fester,
仮に全土統一などという妄言が
成し遂げられたとしても いずれは歪みを生じ
and finally, inevitable destruction.
最後に崩壊するは必定
But before that should befall us...
ならば その前に
You want me to take my troops
and invade Kunekamun?
私に兵を率いて
クンネカムンに攻め込めというのだな
Indeed. I, Genjimaru, shall be your guide.
御意に
このゲンジマルが案内役となりましょう
This was the only thing we
could do for Her Majesty.
クーヤ様には こうするしか他に
道が無かったのです
Please, please save her!
どうか どうかクーヤ様をお救いください
Enough, raise your head.
もういい　頭を上げるんだ
But Genjimaru, even though
you act out of loyalty,
だがゲンジマル 忠義のためとはいえ
お前がしていることは謀反だ
what you are doing is still forbidden.
I believe true loyalty lies in
correcting my master's path.
真の忠義とは
君主の道を正すことにございます
All right...
分かった
Brother!
兄者！
I will trust you. I shall place
our fate in your hands!
信じよう　我らの命運 汝に預ける
You have my gratitude.
感謝いたします
It seems your wounds are fine now.
もう傷は 大丈夫みたいですね
When I first met you, you were tending
to my wounds just like this.
初めて会った時も
こうして君に手当てされていた
That's right. You were injured
after that big earthquake...
そうですね
地震の後の大けがで　あっ…
うん？　どうした？
What's wrong?
Nothing! It was like this the
first time I met you.
いいえ
そうですね 初めて会った時から
Yes...
You supported me when I thought my heart
was going to be torn to pieces.
バラバラになりそうな私の心を
君が支えてくれている
Will you stay by my side from here on too?
これからも そばにいてくれないか？
Yes...
はい
To counter Kunekamun,
クンネカムンに対抗するには
we need to gather the forces
of those who have revolted.
各地で蜂起した反勢力に
協力を求める必要があります
It will be difficult to control all
the small factions.
小規模な連中ばかりを
統制するのは 難しいぞ
It might be possible if we had the time.
時があれば可能でしょうが
There is one who could make this possible.
だが １人だけ
それを可能にする人物がいる
You don't mean...
まさか
Genjimaru...
ゲンジマル
Perhaps we could rescue the High Priest
who is imprisoned on Saharan Island,
サハラン島に捕らわれしオルヤンクルをお救いし
お言葉をいただければ あるいは
and ask him to speak on our behalf.
はっ お父様 生きているの？
Father is alive!?
Yes, the High Priest is imprisoned in
a dungeon on Saharan Island.
はい　オルヤンクルは
サハラン島にある牢に幽閉されております
Sister!
お姉様
Brother!
兄者
ガァーオー
コホッ コホッ
I guess it's getting kind of chilly.
Let's go inside.
冷えてきたみたい　中に入りましょう
Sure...
はい
Eruruu-sama?
エルルゥ様
Yes?
はい
Eruruu-sama, you seem depressed.
エルルゥ様 元気が無いみたい
Not at all...
そんなことは…
Your hands used to be so warm.
温かかった手が こんなに冷たくなってる
They're so cold now.
That's probably because of what I realized.
それはきっと 私が気付いてしまったから
Hakuoro-sama will warm them up again.
また ハクオロ様が温めてくれます
Because the warmth in our hands
comes from those that we love.
だって 手のぬくもりは
大好きな人から伝わるのだから
My brother, Tuskuru-sama, Hakuoro-sama...
お兄様も トゥスクル様も ハクオロ様も
They all have warm hands.
皆温かい
May I come in?
よろしいですか？
えっ は はい
Y... Yes!
Shall we talk?
お話をしませんか
Um... What did you want to talk about?
あの お話って…
It is not something that one should
normally have to deal with.
あれは本来
人が関わって良いものではありません
What do you mean by that?
どういう意味ですか？
It has guided our kind since antiquity.
古の時代から
あれは我らを導いてきました
Then you know, don't you?
知っているんですね
I am a priestess of the Onkamiyamukai,
私はオンカミヤムカイのカムナギ
my destiny is to worship and
protect Witsalnemitea.
ウィツァルネミテアを崇め
見守るのが使命
You knew from the start?
初めから？
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい
I would have preferred never bringing
it up if only it had been possible.
言わずに済むことなら
そうしたかったのですが
There is something that I want to say to you,
as a woman, not a priestess.
カムナギである前に １人の女として
あなたに伝えたいことがあります
That your heart at least belongs to
no one else, it is yours alone.
心だけは 誰のものでもありません
あなたのものなのですよ
あっ 私の… もの？
Mine alone?
That's right.
そう　神の契約でも
つなぎ留めておくことができない 唯一のもの
It is the one thing that cannot be
bound in a pact with the gods.
So, you can still live in a way
that's true to your heart.
あなたは 心のままに生きていいんです
うふっ
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
Let me stay like this a while.
少し このままで
I can hear the sound of life,
the sound of your heartbeat.
心の音です
Everything's going to be all right,
because I can hear this sound.
この音が聞こえているから
大丈夫なんです
Um, can you say it again for me?
あの もう一度言ってもらえませんか
Huh?
What you told me yesterday.
昨日言った 言葉
Sure...
ああ　これからも そばにいてくれないか
Will you stay by my side from here on too?
Yes!
はい
うっ お父様ー！
Father!
I must have had you worried.
心配を掛けたな
Your Holiness!
オルヤンクル
I am glad to see you're safe.
ご無事で何よりです
It is a pleasure to meet you,
Emperor of Tuskuru.
会えてうれしく思います
トゥスクル皇よ
No thanks are necessary.
We had our reasons to rescue you.
礼など不要です
お救いしたのは 訳あってのこと
You need the voice of the High Priest
to unite the various factions?
幾多の部族をまとめるため
オルヤンクルの声が必要なのですな
Yes, please lend us your power.
はい　どうかお力添えを
うーむ
But that is no longer my duty.
ですが それはもはや
私の役目ではありません
Urutori!
ウルトリィ
Yes!
はい
As of this moment, I bestow upon
you the rank of High Priest!
今よりそなたに オルヤンクルの位を譲る
Sister...
お姉様
Urutori-sama...
ウルトリィ様
I accept.
承知いたしました
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
On the Path of Destruction